### **Personal Data**

### <u>Name</u>

Vinod Saggam.

#### Sex

Male.

## **Nationality**

India.

#### **Marital Status**

Single.

#### Languages

English, Hindi, Kannada, Telugu & Marathi

# **Presently Working**

Quess Corp Ltd.

#### **Contact Information**

Mobile: 7892079201

### Email id

Vinodsaggam52@gmail.com

### **Professional Synopsis**

A competent professional with 5+ years of hands-on experience efficiently developing and maintaining web application using Core PHP, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Presently associated with Accenture payroll to Quess Corp Ltd as Senior Software Engineer.

### **Professional Experience**

Accenture payroll to Quess Corp Ltd.

**Senior Software Engineer** – 07 June 2021 – Present.

Friday Media tech India Pvt Ltd. (FMTI)

**Software Developer** – 27 Jan 2020 – 26 April 2021.

Solution Kraft Pvt Ltd. (SK)

Web Developer - Dec 2017 - 17 Jan 2020.

Integrated Intelligent Solutions & Technologies Pvt Ltd. (I<sup>2</sup>ST)

Software Engineer – Jan 2016 – Nov 2017.

Technical	Skills	
Languages:	JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, CSS, HTML	
React Tools:	React.js, Webpack, Redux	
Performance Testing Frameworks:	Mocha, Chai	

### **Key Results:**

- Collaboration as a technical team with product management team in the design and development of web applications.
- Proficient in building web user interface website using HTML, CSS, and BOOTSTRAP, JavaScript and JQUERY.
- Exposure to creating SPA using ReactJS, by using the concept of virtual dom
- ❖ A strong understanding of database-driven web applications.
- Can perform a mix of maintenance, enhancements, and new development as required.
- Comfortable in working on Ubuntu/CentOS and Windows Systems.
- Exposure to Jira, Bitbucket, PhpStorm, Rally, GitHub.

#### **Key Projects Handled at Quess Corp**

Project Name: Web SDK Bot & SKIMM

Client: Comcast USA

**Description**: Working on the USA-based project to enhance and update the application continuous based on

customers feedback and updating new features as requires and test the functionality.

Responsibilities:

 Being assigned with user tasks and implementing new features as the client requires and testing the functionality accordingly

• Developing and maintaining Git repository and establishing a great collaboration among the cross-functional development team

Technology Used: JavaScript, ReactJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Node.js.

Project Name: Xfinity JS & Xfinity JS Docs

Client: Comcast USA

**Description**: Working on the USA-based project to build a boilerplate project to serve as a base for new projects in the upcoming future. My part in this project is to work on the backlog task and features and implement them as the client requires and test the functionality.

Responsibilities: Being assigned with backlog user tasks and implementing new features as the client requires and

testing the functionality accordingly.

**Technology Used:** JavaScript, ReactJS, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Node.js.

## **Key Projects Handled at FMTI**

Project Name: Promoter Project.

Client: Memoria UK

**Description**: This is a Core PHP-based business website that is developed for offline dealers to promote their business online by offering them a custom e-commerce website of their own which can be administrated from another user-specific admin panel website.

**Responsibilities**: Involved in developing a new Theme for the website, enhancements and bug fixing, and hotfixes to live sites.

**Technology Used:** Core PHP, MYSQL, jQuery, HTML, CSS, LESS, Memcached.

Project Name: Niche Market Project – Dogs & Puppies Blog. (Internal Project)

**Description**: This is a Laravel framework-based website that is basically a blog exclusively for dogs and puppies and its sale across the whole UK.

**Responsibilities**: Involved in developing new features, enhancements, and hotfixes for the live site, providing support for bug fixing.

Technology Used: PHP Laravel Framework, MYSQL, jQuery, CSS.

#### **Key Projects Handled at Solution**

**Project Name**: HR Services (Internal Project).

**Description**: This is a web-based project to provide functionalities to the recruitment team for human resource management. To collect the requirement from clients and upload on to the portal and share those requirements with related groups and any others.

Responsibilities: Involved in Requirement Collection, Coding (HTML/PHP), Testing the application, Project

Deployment, and doing development as per requirements.

**Technology Used:** Core PHP, MYSQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax, jQuery, and JSON.

Project Name: iLeap Academia.

**Client**: Infosys BPO.

**Description**: This is a Customized Moodle framework-based project to provide functionalities such as the Creation of new Categories and Courses adding new Assessments, Quiz and book contents, and enrollment of users so that they can access the contents to which they are enrolled.

**Responsibilities**: Involved in development, enhancements, and bug fixing of the project, wrote custom modules and integrated some community modules for the project, providing support for bug fixing, adding of new modules, Handling queries such as the addition of new contents to the portals, and other relative queries.

Technology Used: PHP Moodle Framework, MYSQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax, jQuery, JSON, Moodle.

**Project Name**: SkillUpVarsity (Internal Project).

**Description**: This is a Customized Moodle framework-based project to provide functionalities such as the Creation of new Categories and Courses adding new Assessments, Quiz and book contents, and enrollment of users so that they can access the contents using the assessment key to access the contents and can take an assessment quiz.

**Responsibilities**: Involved in development, enhancements, and bug fixing of the project, wrote custom modules and integrated some community modules for the project, providing support for bug fixing, adding of new modules, Handling queries such as the addition of new contents to the portals, and other relative queries.

**Technology Used:** PHP Moodle Framework, MYSQL, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Ajax, jQuery, JSON.

**Project Name**: ERP Kraft (ERP Project). **Client**: Tectonics Mysuru (Interior Factory)

Role: TL.

**Description**: This is a Yii2 framework-based ERP project which allows integration planning, purchasing inventory, sales, marketing, finance, human resources, and more.

The Application is developed as per the same work process flow which they follow in the furniture factory so that it can be easily integrated into the factory.

**Responsibilities**: Interacting with customers and business analysts to collect the requirements, involved in development, enhancements, and bug fixing of the application, writing custom modules and integrated third-party widgets for the project, providing support for bug fixing, the application has 3 phases, 1<sup>st</sup> phase is completed the remaining are in progress.

Technology Used: PHP Yii2 Framework, MYSQL, Slim API, AWS.

# **Professional Qualification**

#### **B.E Graduate 2010 - 2014**

Specialization: Information Science Engineering

Guru Nanak Dev Engineering College (G.N.D), Bidar University, Bidar with First Class.

# **Educational Qualification**

Course	Board/University	Institute	Year of Passing	CGPA/Percentage
10+2	State Board	M.P.U College, Bidar.	2010	65%
10th	State Board	Seventh-Day Adventist School, Bidar.	2008	69.7%

### **Declaration**

I hereby declare that the details stated above are true to the best of my knowledge and I would like to state that if am given an opportunity, I will work with strong determination and dedication to the best of my abilities.

Place: Bidar Vinod Saggam